In this [music] video, we are going to
talk about the expense agent and namely
going to talk about the new feature that
we added, which is to create mileage
expenses. So, in this case, if you have
a uh employees who are traveling through
I don't know, for a conference uh with
their personal car, they can actually
submit their expense using the mileage
feature in expense agent. So, in order
to do that, I'm just going to go to
uh the web application. I'm going to
click on create mileage expense. As soon
as I do that, you can actually see that
the map is going to load and then I am
able to choose uh a starting point and
an ending point. For that, I'm going to
choose in this case uh Microsoft
soft Denmark.
When I leave here, and then I am going
to travel, for example, in Flensburg,
Germany.
Yes, I'm going to choose the first one.
And then you can actually see that now I
as user can choose up to three different
routes uh and yeah, choose the one that
uh I drove uh through. And of course, I
can expand this. I can choose one of the
three different routes. Let's say that I
actually went on all the bridges.
And then I'm going to choose this one.
Then we automatically um calculate based
on what your admin set uh the rates of
the the miles. So, we automatically
automatically calculate that. Then of
course, if you did uh a round trip, you
can toggle this button, which basically
is just going to double whatever the
distance and the amount was for the
trip. You can choose the date and you
can provide a description. The payment
means is cash by default. And of course,
the categorization is mileage. So, I'm
just going to go ahead and create this
expense. It's as easy uh as you see.
Just going to create it.
And yeah, the expense agent is going to
process it and then it's going to try to
add it to an existing report, try to
match it and so on. And now let's
go on the Business Central admin site to
see how we can actually configure this
mileage expense.
I'm in my Business Central tenant and as
you already are used to to the avatars
of the agents, I'm going to go through
the expense agent avatar.
I'm going to click on the settings
button.
Then I'm going to go through the
mileage expenses slide and you can
actually calculate the rate per unit.
You can set it to one. Let's say that in
this case I don't know I want
to 0.50. And of course you can also
yeah, the select the default unit of
distance. In this case it's miles, but
of course we also allow kilometers. So
I'm just going to switch to that and I'm
going to update it. In addition to that,
as you have seen,
I was able to select multiple routes.
And this is done by going to the expense
agent setup. So I searched for the page,
I went to the expense agent setup page
and there's a configuration on the
allowance tab which says only shortest
route. In this case it's toggled off
which means that I as a user can choose
multiple routes actually to for
traveling. But if I was to enable this
toggle, then the expense agent would
would always pick the shortest route to
between the starting point and the
destination. I hope you enjoyed this
video. This is the mileage feature in
the expense agent
application and thank you for watching.